Melissa Kaylor

Copywriter

Dallas, TX = 469.260.7579 = melissawritescopy@gmail.com

A versatile copywriter with 7+ years of experience writing copy for both print and digital mediums. A collaborative and strategic thinker with a successful history of developing campaigns for a range of industries and audiences. Additional experience includes proofreading, brand review, rebranding, brand management, marketing management, social media writing and management, account planning, SEO, and market research.

Areas of expertise

- Copywriting and copyediting
- Branding and compliance
- Publication management
- Social media management
- Competitive analysis
- Project management
- Market research
- AP style
- SEO copywriting

Professional experience

Andra Group, Dallas, TX, April 2018 - Present Copywriter

- Write original content for email campaigns, fronts, lookbooks and product guides
- Collaborate with graphic designers to create compelling campaigns and increase sales
- Sole brand reviewer on all collateral, social media posts and internal documents with an emphasis on voice consistency and brand compliance
- Improve SEO performance by writing strategically-targeted blogs and optimized content for main department landing pages

Vizient, Inc., Irving, TX, September 2016 – September 2017 Copywriter and Brand Review Manager – Contract

- Brand reviewed content for internal and external emails, fact sheets, landing pages, brochures, whitepapers, case studies, banners, event collateral and signage
- Proofread copy for business units including supply chain operations, clinical operations, sales enablement, consulting and events
- Developed and executed new marketing communications
- Supported key marketing initiatives with brand review and brand conversion
- Created style guidance documents and writer templates for internal use

Nerium International, Addison, TX, May 2015 - August 2016 Copywriter - Creative Services & Branding (Retail, Opportunity, Events, Skincare, Health)

- Proofread packaging and kit material copy for new and revamped products, while also working with translators in French, Spanish, Korean, and Japanese to support international expansion
- Spearheaded concepts and content for print and digital mediums, including blog posts, event collateral, monthly publications, social media posts and kit materials
- Developed clear, concise messaging for a variety of materials supporting marketing initiatives

Talent Inc., New York, NY, April 2014 – April 2018 Resume, Cover Letter and LinkedIn Profile Writer – Remote

- Wrote, structured and optimized resumes, cover letters, LinkedIn profiles and other careerrelated documents on a case-by-case basis for job seekers
- Provided personalized support and counseling clients as needed

iWebContent, Dallas, TX, September 2014 – March 2015 Special Projects Manager, Content Writer and Editor

- Created blogs, site content, articles, eBooks and additional content for a range of clients, including hotels
- Monitored, compiled and presented analytics to clients regularly using Excel
- Trained and assisted writers with completing assignments
- Managed client and company social media accounts and created editorial calendars using Excel

Parago, Inc., Lewisville, TX, October 2013 – June 2014 Assistant Marketing Manager

- Aided CEO and Marketing Manager of global incentive marketing firm with internal and external marketing operations
- Provided social media training sessions and materials for executives and employees
- Managed corporate social media efforts, increasing qualified monthly leads by 10%

VLG Agency and BakedSoft LLC, Plano, TX, June 2012 - March 2013 Interactive Copywriter and Brand Manager

- Brainstormed and developed concepts for online interactive experiences
- Pitched and sold concepts to clients using PowerPoint theme decks
- Launched all public facing communications for connected software start-up
- Wrote all in-app and app store copy
- Worked with vendors to commission merchandise development
- Performed beta testing prior to releasing apps

AvreaFoster, Dallas, TX, January 2012 - June 2012 Copywriter - Contract

 Collaborated with art directors to create a variety of print and digital campaigns for a range of clients, some including FASTSIGNS, Omni Hotels & Resorts, The Texas Rangers and Medical City

EnviroMedia Social Marketing, Austin, TX, 2011-2012 Copywriter - Contract, January 2012 Copywriter - Intern, Summer June 2011 - August 2011

 Worked on campaigns for several clients, including Don't Mess With Texas, Pay It Forward Foundation, Worth It?, and Water IQ

American Advertising Federation, Austin, TX, July 2011 – December 2012 Assistant Program Coordinator, Stickell Advertising Internship Program

- Coordinated a nationwide internship program for the nation's top undergraduate advertising students and firms
- Worked with a designer to create a brochure highlighting the interns' experiences at the end of the term

University of Texas, Communications Department, Austin, TX, July 2011 - December 2012 Graduate Assistant, Advertising Concepts Undergraduate Class

- Acted as professor's primary assistant for a class of over 500 undergraduate advertising students
- Wrote, scored, and recorded grades for exams and class projects using Excel
- Planned and taught tri-weekly supplemental instruction sessions designed to help students better understand the curriculum
- Students who regularly attended supplemental instruction sessions proved to have a much higher pass rate, resulting in admittance into the university's advertising program

Education

M.A., Advertising (Copywriting: Texas Creative Sequence), University of Texas, Austin, TX B.A., Advertising Marketing and Psychology, University of North Texas, Denton, TX